Contact

eababaa@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ elizabethbabaa (LinkedIn) www.instagram.com/ aesthetics.eliz/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Nursing BLS ACLS

Languages

English

Certifications

Trauma Nursing Core Course (TNCC)

DEA

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support (ACLS)

Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN)
Pediatric Advanced Life Support
(PALS)

Elizabeth Babaa

Nurse Practitioner, Cosmetic Injector
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

Nurse Practitioner, Cosmetic Injector:

As a nurse practitioner, I serve the population and their families with compassion, knowledge, and expertise in holistic health care practices. Applying emergency, urgent care, and aesthetic experience I exercise evidence-based clinical judgement and decision making to diagnose and treat varying illnesses while emphasizing health promotion and disease prevention. My determination, positive perspective, and exceptional work ethic would be a substantial asset to any organization.

Experience

SKINIQUE MED SPA & WELLNESS Nurse Practitioner, Cosmetic Injector May 2020 - Present (3 months)

Sona Dermatology & MedSpa Nurse Practitioner, Clinical Manager January 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 3 months) Fort Worth, Texas

- -Subject matter expert on aesthetic services, dermatologic treatments, and skin care products.
- -Ensures safe treatment clearance for patients by completing history taking and physical examination with special attention to potential contraindications.
- -Performs high-quality treatments using procedure and protocol to achieve patient satisfaction (i.e. cosmetic injectables, skin resurfacing, laser hair removal, and fat reduction).
- -Prevents, monitors, and manages all patient adverse reactions.
- -Upholds management responsibilities, including provider evaluations, chart audits, and maintaining center compliance.
- -Supports provider staff with up-to-date training, performance counseling, and reward recognition.

-Contributes to company protocol and procedure by reviewing and revising treatment guidelines.

CareNow

Nurse Practitioner - Urgent Care, Family Practice July 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 3 months)

Fort Worth, Texas

- -Autonomously uses history taking and physical assessment to diagnose, treat, and manage acute and chronic conditions in a fast-pace urgent care environment. Collaborates with other healthcare professionals when needed.
- -Orders and interprets diagnostic testing in the patients' best interest; including STAT radiology, 12-lead electrocardiogram, blood work, urinalysis, and other various measurements.
- -Performs minor procedures with confidence; such as laceration repair, trigger-point injections, toe nail removal, incision & drainage, and other skin procedures.
- -Assists and educates patients in making better lifestyle and health choices with both non-pharmacologic therapies and prescription pharmacological agents.
- -Ensures patient safety and satisfaction by establishing rapport and building strong relationships.
- -Directs and oversees patient flow; manages staff interactions and responsibilities as needed.

Baylor Scott & White Health Registered Nurse, Clinical Coach - Emergency Department June 2014 - October 2018 (4 years 5 months)

Fort Worth, Texas

- -Provides direct patient care and establishes safety practices by administering medications, monitoring patient assessments, and verifying orders as appropriate.
- -Completes, coordinates, and delegates patient care in a continuously changing environment while collaborating with multiple disciplines to create positive outcomes for patients and families.
- -Ensures the productiveness of the department meets standards of safety and patient rights while educating patients, family, and staff on medical care, procedures, and visit expectations.
- -Trains new-hires and graduate nurse interns in performance of duties, including standards of service excellence.

-Provides strong supervisory and leadership skills by providing communication, availability, and transparency.

Best Buy

Sales Consultant

January 2010 - May 2014 (4 years 5 months)

Rockwall/Arlington, TX

- Support and assist achievement of store sales and overall customer experience.
- Utilize knowledge and understanding of technology to satisfy client expectations.

Education

Texas Woman's University

Master of Science - MS, Family Nurse Practitioner · (2015 - 2018)

The University of Texas at Arlington

Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2010 - 2014)

Eastfield College

Nursing Pre-Requisites · (2010 - 2013)